ADRIENNE DAO

Address: Arlington, Virginia 22205 Phone: 571.268.4341 Email: adriennedao@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/adriennedao LinkedIn: https://ca.linkedin.com/in/adrienne-dao

DRUPAL WEB DEVELOPER

Summary of Qualifications

Performance-driven, highly analytical, and multifaceted professional, with background in creating websites, configuring network, and setting-up desktop computers; complemented with strong knowledge in general web function and standards. Full stack developer specialized in Drupal 8 development. Equipped with articulate communication and interpersonal aptitudes, combined with ability to build positive work relationships with all levels of organization.

	Technical Acumen		
	Languages	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, SASS, PHP, Object Oriented with PHP, and Python	
•	CMS	Drupal 8, Composer, Drush, Drupal Console, Twig, and Drupal API	
•	Version Control	Git, Git Work Flows, Advanced Git, GitHub, and Heroku	
•	Methodologies	MVC, OOP, TDD, REST, and Agile Methodologies	

Professional Experience

HOPE ONE SOURCE, WASHINGTON, DC

Drupal 8 Developer (Volunteer-Based)

Iun 2018-Present

- Coordinate with team lead in providing assistance to the non-profit organization on the migration operating system from Drupal 7 to Drupal 8
- Utilize Bootstrap, SASS, and Drupal best practice in developing front-end web development, theme, and subtheme
- Lead the integration of third-party applications by using GitHub, Slack, and Trello
- Initiate the creation of repository for mission of the non-profit organization
- Facilitate weekly meeting through Slack Call to update the team on progress of Drupal 8 migration
- Maintain active involvement in various fundraising activities for the non-profit organization

UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF STATES, WASHINGTON, DC

Technical Mentor, ImpactHack (Volunteer-Based)

Sep 2018

- Functioned effectively as the technical mentor for participants of 16 teams in demonstrating diplomacy's impact from local state economies to global issues by using their coding and design skills
- Made significant contribution in the first data visualization hackathon of the organization partnered with United States Diplomacy Center and World Resources Institutes which was sponsored by Amazon Web Services

DEBUG ACADEMY, MCLEAN, VA

Drupal 8 Development

Jan 2018–Apr 2018

Utilized HTML, CSS, SASS, Responsive design, Drupal console, PHP object-oriented Programming, Drupal API, and Hooks system on hands-on Enterprise Drupal 8 development

Web Developer

Project Name: Publish Own Site Syndicate Elsewhere (POSSE)

Technologies Used: Drupal 8

Main Function/Objective: To establish portfolio and blog sites by using the Drupal best practices

EMBASSY OF FRANCE, WASHINGTON, DC

Feb 2017

- Managed the French hacked-mobility
- Efficiently interfaced with a team of UX designers and data scientist for French Education Hackathon
- Took charge of conducting competitive analysis and usability testing

GENERAL ASSEMBLY, WASHINGTON, DC

Full-Time Web Development Immersive

Oct 2016-Dec 2016

- Developed full-stack RESTful web applications
- Generated user-friendly front-end experience by utilizing HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and jQuery with AngularJS and ReactJS frameworks

ADRIENNE DAO

Address: Arlington, Virginia 22205 Phone: 571.268.4341 Email: adriennedao@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/adriennedao LinkedIn: https://ca.linkedin.com/in/adrienne-dao

Projects:

Project Name: Recipe Application

Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, and Ruby/Rails

Main Function/Objective: To develop an application for recipes and ingredients with CRUD functionality

Project Name: Community Application

Technologies Used: AngularJS, Ruby on Rails API, HTML, and CSS

Main Function/Objective: To create an application that feature submitted product ideas of user and contribute to social good

Collaborated with two teammates in building the application

Project Name: TravelBlog Application

Technologies Used: Ruby, Rails, and PostgreSQL

Main Function/Objective: To produce an application for traveler's in blogging travel experience

FREELANCE

Foreign Language Assistant Instructor

Jan 2012–Dec 2015

- Taught one-on-one conversation class to English native speakers

THE GEORGE WASHINGTON UNIVERSITY, WASHINGTON, DC

Facilities Management | Systems Specialist

Aug 2000-Jul 2011

- Rendered effective desktop technical support to the Department of Facilities Management regarding Microsoft Windows
- Spearheaded the constant operation of over 125 computer peripherals and all telecommunication equipment
- Leveraged industry expertise in configuring network, installing software, updating personal computers and setting up desktop computers and peripherals
- Worked collaboratively with vendors and service contractors in organizing maintenance and repairs
- Dealt with identifying and troubleshooting all computer-related issues
- Performed extensive research and provided suggestion on software and hardware purchases
- Delivered high level of assistance with the set-up of NetWare 6.0 and Windows 2000 server in accordance with writing policy and procedure for the System Administration Department

Education and Credentials

Angular 5 (Online Course), Aug 2018

Udemy.com

React and Drupal 8, Apr 2018

Debug Academy

Learn Node.js | ES 6 | React for beginners (Online Courses), Aug 2017

Wes Bos

Drupal 8 Web Development, Apr 2018

Debug Academy, McLean, VA

Web Development Immersive Program, Dec 2016

General Assembly, Washington, DC

Information Technologies

The George Washington University, College of Professional Studies, Washington, DC

Bachelor of Arts in French and Business Translations

University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA

Affiliation

Drupal Association, 2018-Present

Activities

Participant | Inforum 2018 Conference, Walter E. Convention Center, Washington, DC

Junior Change Agent | Hope One Source, Arlington, VA

Participant | Drupal 4 Government Conference, NIH Bethesda, MD

Contributor | Drupal 8 Hope One Source Sprint, Arlington, VA

Contributor | Barrier-Free Contribution Sprint, Debug Academy

Participant | Baltimore Drupal Camp, Baltimore, MD